Welcome to our used sold as new product compliance training.
A used sold as new product condition issue occurs when a customer receives a product
that isn't in the new condition they expected.
If a product's detail page states the product is new when the customer receives the product,
it must be in new condition.
Noncompliance with Amazon's preventing product condition issues and condition guidelines policies
may affect your ability to sell in the Amazon store.
Customers may perceive a product to have been previously used when it's scratched,
scuffed, dirty, odorous, stained, or has other imperfections that indicate it's been used.
Its packaging has been previously opened or damaged.
The product isn't in its original unopened packaging or when the product or packaging seal
is missing or broken.
Let's meet Sophia, who sells multiple products in the Amazon store.
She monitors what her customers say about her products by signing in to Seller Central
and reviewing buyer messages using the buyer seller messaging service,
customer feedback, product reviews, A to Z claims, returns,
the customer complaint summary, and the voice of the customer dashboard.
Sophia ensures that she sets accurate expectations for her customers
by clearly describing the condition of her products on the product detail pages.
When she lists each of her products, Sophia makes sure that she chooses the correct
condition from the drop-down list.
She only chooses new if her product is truly in new condition.
Note that not all stores have the option to list used products.
Here are some tips to prevent noncompliance with Amazon's preventing product condition issues
policy and condition guidelines.
Tip 1.
Describe your products and their packaging clearly on the product detail pages.
Tip 2.
Regularly carry out quality audits to review your quality control processes.
Tip 3.
Inspect your products to ensure they function correctly and match their descriptions
on the detail pages.
Tip 4.
Ensure your staff are trained to prevent issues with both new and returned products.
Tip 5.
Check to determine if your products have any defects or issues.
Tip 6.
Select appropriate packaging and shipping for your product.
Use bubble wrap and other
protective packaging and ensure the packaging's design is suitable for the product and its handling.
Customers often perceive products with damaged or open packaging to have been previously used.
Tip 7.
Store your products where they'll remain clean, dry, and at the correct temperature.
Tip 8.
Never return a product to sellable inventory when the product's seal has been broken
and always label and store your returned products separately from new products to avoid any confusion.
Don't forget that you may only resell returned products as new if they meet the
condition guidelines for a new product and show no signs of use.
You can find the condition guidelines by going to Seller Central and searching for condition
guidelines in the search field at the top of the page.
Remember to keep your account health from
being negatively impacted by used sold as new product condition complaints.
Always ensure that
your customer receives the product in the condition as described on the product detail page.
This concludes our training on used sold as new product compliance.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!